# Matthew DongKyu Cho

GRADUATE RESEARCHER @ SEOUL NATIONAL UNIVERSITY · RESEARCH SCIENTIST INTERN @ LG AI RESEARCH

💌 kulupapa1127@snu.ac.kr | 😭 umamicode.github.io | 🖸 github.com/umamicode | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/umamicode



#### Personal Profile

A graduate researcher in the Graduate School of Data Science, Seoul National University, advised by Professor Sanghack Lee. Currently a Research Scientist Intern at LG Al Research, Data Intelligence Lab. My research interests include Causal Representation Learning and Domain Generalization.

### Education

#### **Seoul National University**

Seoul, South Korea

Master of Science in Data Science

March 2021 - Current

- · Advised by Professor Sanghack Lee
- Courses: Machine Learning and Deep Learning for Data Science, Big Data and Knowledge Management Systems, Software Platforms for Data Science, Machine Learning for Visual Understanding, Text Analytics and Big Data, Causal Inference for Data Science, Special Topics in Data Science: Meta Learning, Data Science Capstone Project, Dissertation Research, Special Lecture on Data Science

**Seoul National University** Seoul, South Korea

Bachelor of Arts in Information Science and Culture / Western History (Double Major)

March 2014 - February 2021

- Graduated with Distinction (Cum Laude)
- Data-Driven Marketing Project with Local Stitch

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**LG AI Research** Seoul, South Korea

Research Scientist Intern July 2023 - Present

· Causality-Driven Prediction & Optimization for Decision-Making

**Causality Lab (SNU GSDS)** Seoul, South Korea

Graduate Research Assistant July 2021 - Present

• Collaborative Research Projects with corporate partners (NH Investments & LG AI Research)

**VAIV Company (Former DaumSoft)** 

Seoul, South Korea Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

• Data-Driven Market Analysis for corporate clients.

**Republic of Korea Armed Forces** Icheon, South Korea Military Interpreter March 2016 - December 2017

• Military Interpreter for the Republic of Korea Armed Forces.

#### • Technical Skills: Korean-English Interpretation

#### Research

Analyst Intern

## Distillation-based Single Source Domain Generalization via Mutual Information Regularization

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University Causality Lab

Working Paper (Under Review)

• Keywords: Causal Representation Learning, Domain Generalization

## **DELPHI: Leveraging Self Knowledge as Teachers for Out-of-domain Robustness**

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University Causality Lab

Working Paper

• Keywords: Causal Representation Learning, Domain Generalization, Continual Learning

JULY 7, 2023

**Projects** 

#### Stock Interrelation Research using Keyword and Supply Chain data

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University and NH Investment & Securities

July 2021 - August 2022

- A collaborative research with NH Investment & Securities.
- A learning pipeline for a Financial Language Model
- Interactive Graph Database using the Bloomberg Supply Chain Data.
- Technical Skills: Financial-Domain specific Language Models, Financial Data, Graph Database.

#### **Towards Language Models Capable of Causal Reasoning**

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University and LG AI Research

August 2022 - Present

- Collaborative research with LG AI Research & UNIST
- A Causal NLP Project Under Progress
- Technical Skills: Causal Inference, Large-scale Language Models.

Class Projects Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University

March 2021 - July 2023

- Class Project for Special Topics in Data Science- Meta Learning: "Semi-Supervised Federated Learning with Representations"
- Class Project for Machine Learning for Visual Understanding: "A combination approach for wikipedia Image/Caption Matching Competition"

## **Skills**

**Programming** Python, R, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Neo4j, ŁTEX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Git.

**Soft Skills** French, Korean, English-Korean Interpretation

# **Languages**

**English** Professional proficiency/ TOEFL 118 (2020.08), 116 (2022.08)

**Korean** Native proficiency

**French** Intermediate proficiency/ DELF B1

JULY 7, 2023